Daehwa Kim

291, Daehak-ro, Yuseong-gu, Daejeon, Republic of Korea daehwakim@kaist.ac.kr • +82 6860 8558 • https://daehwa.github.io

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research goal is engineering for a fluid interface, exploring a seamless integration of a computer and human that makes new and pleasant experiences. My prior research lies in (a) sensing and interaction techniques for a mobile device and (b) novel sensing technologies supporting sophisticated hand inputs. I published full papers at ACM CHI and UIST.

Sensing Techniques	novel sensing technologies supporting sophisticated hand inputs	sensing and interaction techniques for a mobile device
for Fluid Interfaces	 AtaTouch (Cond. Accepted CHI'21) + MagTouch (CHI'20) 	OddEyeCam (UIST'20)OmniSense (Ongoing)

EDUCATION

KAIST, School of Computing

Mar 2019 - Feb 2021 (Expected)

- M.S. student at Human-Computer Interaction Lab
 - Thesis: "OddEyeCam: Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interaction Using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras" (To be)
 - Adviser: Prof. Geehyuk Lee
 - Focus: Sensing Techniques

UNIST, Electrical and Computer Engineering

Mar 2015 - Feb 2019

- B.S. in Computer Science and Engineering (Major)
 - B.S. in Electrical Engineering (Minor)
 - Thesis: "VRone: 3D Force Feedback System in VR Using a Commercial Drone"
 - Entered with top honors.
- Summer session program, ual: (University of the Arts London), London, UK

Jul 2018

PUBLICATIONS

CONFERENCES

- [1] <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee, "AtaTouch: Robust Finger Pinch Detection for a VR Controller Using RF Return-Loss" in *Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, Yokohama, Japan. (full paper, Conditionally Accepted)
- [2] <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee, "OddEyeCam: A Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interaction Using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras" in *Proceedings of the 33rd Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology*, Virtual Event, USA, Oct 2020. (full paper)
- [3] Keunwoo Park, <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Seongkook Heo, and Geehyuk Lee, "MagTouch: Robust Finger Identification for a Smartwatch Using a Magnet Ring and a Built-in Magnetometer" in *Proceedings of the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, Honolulu, Hawaii, USA, Apr 2020. (full paper)

SUBMITTED

[1] Hui-Shyong Yeo, Erwin Wu, <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Juyoung Lee, Hyung-il Kim, Luna Takagi, Woontack Woo, Hideki Koike, and Aaron J Quigley, "OmniSense: Exploring Novel Input Sensing and Interaction Techniques on Mobile Device with OmniDirectional Camera" in *Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, Yokohama, Japan. (full paper)

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

HCI Lab, KAIST

- Undergraduate Research Student, School of Computing
 - Project: PCB design for a hand gesture sensing wristband.
 - Supervisors: Prof. Geehyuk Lee
 - Focus: PCB design

Hyper-connected Communication Research Laboratory, ETRI

- Research Intern, IoT Research Division
 - Project: Smart Home project Building IoT lighting system controlled by user's voice
 - Supervisors: Dr Jungsik Sung and Daeho Kim

Jan 2018 - Mar 2018

Mar 2018 - Jun 2018

· Focus: IoT network system, Natural language processing iHCI Lab (Intelligent Human Computer Interaction Lab), UNIST • Undergraduate Research Student, Electrical and Computer Engineering Feb 2017 - Nov 2017 • Project: Finger Joystick Interaction • Supervisors: Prof. Sungahn Ko • Focus: human-computer interaction, visualization **4th Prize**, NAVER x UNIST Undergraduate Poster Award Dec 2017 **AWARDS & SCHOLARSHIPS** • Topic: "VibCat: Vibration Categorization for Input and Interaction". Awarded by NAVER CEO. Received an award of 1.000.000 KRW. Excellence Award, World Friends ICT volunteers return report 2016 Dec 2016 Dispatched to Uzbekistan to provide Android development lectures to university students. Awarded by the Director of National Information Society Agency. Received an award of Samsung Galaxy Tab 4 10.1. Academic Achievement Award, UNIST ■ 2017 Fall Academic Achievement Award: GPA 4.05/4.3 Jan 2018 2017 Spring Academic Achievement Award: GPA 3.98/4.3 Jul 2017 2016 Fall Academic Achievement Award: GPA 3.90/4.3 Feb 2016 2016 Spring Academic Achievement Award: GPA 4.06/4.3 Aug 2016 2015 Spring Academic Achievement Award: GPA 4.00/4.3 Jul 2015 Mar 2015 – Feb 2019 Uni-Star Scholarship, UNIST • Entered with top honors. ■ Tuition + academic support fee of 1,000,000 KRW were paid each semester. Overseas Training Scholarship, UNIST Jun 2018 • Financial aid for the summer session program at University of the Arts London **Teaching Assistant**, AI Lab - Learning Commons II, UNIST Sep 2018 – Dec 2018 **TEACHING EXPERIENCE** Head of Android Developement Team, HeXA, UNIST Feb 2017 - Dec 2017 **Instructor**, Tashkent University of Information Technologies (TUIT) Jul 2016 - Sep 2016 • Excellence Award, World Friends ICT volunteers return report 2016 **CAMPUS D2** factory, NAVER **ACTIVITIES** Campus Partner Feb 2016 - Feb 2017 • Hosted the 2nd Hackathon at UNIST, sponsored by NAVER and UNIST ECE HeXA (Hacker's eXciting Academy), UNIST • A computer security & development research group Feb 2016 - Feb 2017 Vice-President Head of Android development team Feb 2017 - Dec 2017 • Provided regular anndroid-development lectures for club members **UNIST Media Center**, UNIST Video Editor Mar 2015 – Feb 2017 Representative work · My Age 22 - Travel to Europe with a drone • Web drama: The town where engineers live **PROJECTS Audio Hero** Sep 2019 - Dec 2019 Sound-based danger detection system using VGGish deep learning model Skills: Deep learning, Signal processing **VRone** Sep 2018 – Dec 2018 3-dimensional force feedback in VR using a personal and commercial drone • Skills: Unity C# programming, Android programming System Light 2.0 @ ETRI Jan 2018 - Mar 2018 • Smart Home project - Building IoT system for lights

Oct 2017 - Dec 2017

• Skills: Computer network, Natural language processing

VibCat

- Vibration Categorization for Input & Interaction
- Skills: Machine learning, Android programming

Finger joystick interaction

Feb 2017 - Nov 2017

- Interaction technique to support finger's directional input using capacitive image of a smartwatch's touchscreen
- Skills: Machine learning, Android programming

Poem a moment

Mar 2017 – Jun 2017

- An android application that shows Yoon Dongju's poems on the wallpaper
- Available on Google Play store (download 1000+)
- Skills: Android programming

TUIT Android Lecture

Jun 2016 - Sep 2016

- Android development lecture provided to TUIT university students
- Skills: Android programming, Object-oriented programming

Mr.Bill

Jun 2016 - Jul 2016

- Algorithm and system to provide optimal Dutch pay way
- Available on Google Play store (download 500+)
- Skills: Android programming, Graph theory

[CV compiled on 2020-12-13 for Acme Corporation]